A Finding Aid to the Will Barnet Papers, 1938-2001, in the Archives of American Art AAA.barnwill
Archives of American Art
- Writings, 1940-2000; Series 3; 3.1 Linear feet Boxes 5-9
  - By Will Barnet, 1945-1998; 3.1
    - Speech, On Art, circa 1950-1970; 1 sound tape reels (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous Notes, circa 1960-2000 (Box 8, Folder 9-10)
    - Miscellaneous Writings, circa 1950-1970 (Box 8, Folder 11-15)
  - By Others, 1940-2000; 3.2
    - Barnet, Peter, Will Barnet: Artist and Teacher, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Farnesworth Art Museum, Docent Talk, 1996; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Farrell, James T., Writings on Will Barnet, 1940-1949 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Flexner, James, "Will Barnet", 1990 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Frankel, Jack, Providers (play), circa 1990-2000 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Grant, Daniel, On Becoming an Artist (draft), 2000 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Gray, Robert, "Will Barnet... Remembrance of Things Present", circa 1960-1975 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Gursoy, Ahmet, A New Yorker by Choice, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Kuh, Katherine, "Sitting for Will", 1983 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - MacDonald, Michael, "Eighth Street Past", circa 1970-1990 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Morley, Grace, "Abstract Art on the Pacific Coast", circa 1960-1975 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Newsom, Patricia, "Will Barnet", circa 1960-1975 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Rehl, Beatrice, "World in a Frame", 1990 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Savelli, Angelo, Lecture, 1973; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Stillwell, Mary Kathryn, Poems, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Wolfe, Townsend, Speech at Arkansas Art Center, 1992; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Miscellaneous, cirac 1960-1975 (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Exhibition Guest Register, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - Exhibition Guest Register, 1970-1976 (Box 9, Folder 1-3)
- Personal Business Records, 1950-1981; Series 4; 5 Folders Box 9
  Personal business records include sales and teaching contracts, gift acknowledgements, price lists, and income tax forms that pertain to art sales and income.
  Items are arranged by document type.
  - Contracts and Forms, 1950-1975 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Gift Acknowledgements, 1952-1976 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Income Tax, 1966-1975 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Price Lists, circa 1950-1980 (Box 9, Folder 7-8)
- Printed Material and Publications, 1938-2001; Series 5; 2.3 Linear feet Boxes 9-11
  Printed material and publications include auction catalogs, clippings, audio recordings (2 sound cassettes), video documentaries (15 VHS videocassettes), exhibition announcements and catalogs, newsletters, press releases, programs, and reproductions of artwork. Publications also include two books, including Will Barnet, Prints 1932-1964 and Artist's Cookbook, which includes a recipe from Barnet. Documentaries of note include Artist's Eye and Lasting Impressions, both of which Barnet contributed interviews to, and an audio tour of Stuart Davis' 1992 exhibition at the Metropolitan Museum of Art.
  - Printed Material, 1938-2001; 5.1
    - Clippings, circa 1930-1980 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Clippings, 1937-1972 (Box 9, Folder 10-14)
    - Clippings, 1973-1977 (Box 9, Folder 15-19)
    - Clippings, 1978-1982 (Box 9, Folder 20-24)
    - Clippings, 1983-2001 (Box 9, Folder 25-30)
    - Press Releases, 1952-1991 (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - Program Flyers, 1958-1979 (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - Reproduction of Artwork, Prints, circa 1950-1980 (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - Reproductions of Artwork, Publication Reprints, circa 1950-1980 (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - Miscellaneous, circa 1950-1980 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Publications, 1938-2001; 5.2
    - Audio Exhibition Tour, Stuart Davis, 1992; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 9, Folder 36)
    - Audio Talks, Mars Hill Tapes, circa 1980-1989; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 9, Folder 37)
    - Auction Catalog, Cooper-Hewitt Museum, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 38)
    - Auction Catalog, National Arts Club, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 39)
    - Book, Artist's Cookbook, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 40)
    - Book, Will Barnet, Prints 1932-1964, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 41)
    - Documentary, Artist's Eye, panel discussion, 1997; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 9, Folder 42)
    - Documentary, Artist's Eye, 1997; 4 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 10, Folder 1-2)
      3 VHS cassettes are additional copies
    - Documentary, Lasting Impressions, 1997; 5 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 10, Folder 3-4)
    - Documentary, Lasting Impressions, unedited version, 1997; 3 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Documentary, Joseph Stapleton, circa 1980-1990; 1 Videocassettes (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Documentary, Roy Neuberger, circa 1980-1990; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, circa 1930-1980 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1938-1968 (Box 10, Folder 9-13)
    - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1970-1976 (Box 10, Folder 14-18)
    - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1977-1981 (Box 11, Folder 1-5)
    - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1982-1989 (Box 11, Folder 6-10)
    - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1990-1994 (Box 11, Folder 11-14)
    - Guide, College Board Collection of Prints by American Artists, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Journal, Rhthmes et Couleurs, 1960 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Newsletters, 1950-1990 (Box 11, Folder 17)
- Photographic Materials, 1939-2001; Series 6; 0.5 Linear feet Box 11, OV 12
  Photographic materials document people, artwork, exhibition installations, and works of art. There are early photos of Barnet teaching at the Art League, as well as photos of Barnet in his studio and with friends and family. Views of exhibition installations and events mainly document solo shows, award ceremonies, and Barnet's reception after receiving the National Arts Club's Gold Medal.
  Items are arranged by material type.
  - Will Barnet with Others, 1939-1969 (Box 11, Folder 18-21)
  - Will Barnet with Others, 1970-2001 (Box 11, Folder 22-24)
  - Friends and Others, 1943-1970 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Event, National Arts Club Gold Medal Award, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Exhibition, Academy of Fine Arts, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Exhibition, Associated American Artists Retrospective, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 28-29)
  - Exhibition, Art Student's League, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Exhibition, Benjamin Galerie, circa 1950-1970 (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Exhibition, Grippi Waddell, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Exhibition, Hirschel and Adler, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - Exhibition, Hirschel and Adler, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - Exhibition, Jane Haslem Gallery, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - Exhibition, Kokusai Bunka Shinkokai, 1952 (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - Exhibition, Neuberger Museum, circa 1950-1970 (Box 11, Folder 37)
  - Exhibition, Unidentified, circa 1950-1970 (Box 11, Folder 38)
  - Photographs of Artwork, Abstracts, 1930s-1960s, circa 1950-1970 (Box 11, Folder 39)
  - Photographs of Artwork, Figurative, 1930s-1960s, circa 1950-1970 (Box 11, Folder 40)
  - Photographs of Artwork, Groups and Animals, 1960s-1970s, circa 1960-1970 (Box 11, Folder 41)
  - Photographs of Artwork, Men, 1960s-1970s, circa 1960-1970 (Box 11, Folder 42)
  - Photographs of Artwork, Woman and Child, 1960s-1970s, circa 1960-1970 (Box 11, Folder 43)
  - Photographs of Artwork, Young Girl, 1960s-1970s, circa 1960-1970 (Box 11, Folder 44)
  - Photographs of Artwork, Young Woman, 1960s-1970s, circa 1960-1970 (Box 11, Folder 45)
  - Photographs of Artwork, Women, 1960s-1970s, circa 1960-1970 (Box 11, Folder 46)
  - Photographs of Artwork, Circular Frames, 1970s, circa 1970-1979 (Box 11, Folder 47)
  - Photographs of Artwork, Woodcuts, circa 1960-1970 (Box 11, Folder 48)
  - Negatives of Artwork, circa 1960-1990 (Box 11, Folder 49)
  - Slides of Artwork, circa 1959-1967 (Box 11, Folder 50)
  - Photographs of Slides and Artwork by Others, circa 1950-1970 (Box 11, Folder 51)
  - Oversized Photographs from Box 11, Folder 22 and 24, 1970-2001 (Box OV 12)
- Artwork, 1938-1983; Series 7; 3 Folders Box 11
  Artwork consists of ink, pencil, and pen sketches by Will Barnet, and a drawing by Bill Smith.
  - Ink and Wash Sketches, circa 1938 (Box 11, Folder 52)
  - Pencil and Pen Sketches, circa 1950-1983 (Box 11, Folder 53)
  - Drawing by Bill Smith, circa 1950-1983 (Box 11, Folder 54)